# **Islam Sabyr**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**)** (+1) 737-235-9938

Houston, TX 77498

# Summary.

Proactive and personable job seeker currently pursuing a Bachelor's of Computer Science at North American University. Excellent written and verbal communication skills. An ambitious student with excellent research, time management, and problem-solving. Hard-working and organized in any type of task that is given to me, I believe my enthusiasm and specialized experience would make me an asset to your team

# Work Experience -

### Computer Programming Tutor North American University

August 2020 - December 2020

Houston, Texas

- · Taught students struggling with Java, HTML & CSS
- · Incorporated technology into lessons from other subjects, expanding students' technical abilities with integrated approach
- · Reviewed computer science class material with students to support discovery of correct answers to problems
- · Tracked and analyzed student progress to provide relevant feedback to students
- · Organized schedules to effectively help students excel and maximize revenue with robust calendar of sessions
- Instructed a wide range of in various areas of Computer Science

Math Tutor August 2020 - December 2020

#### **North American University**

Houston, Texas

- Taught students struggling with Algebra, Calculus or Precalculus
- · Spearheaded group tutoring sessions to help students struggling in similar areas
- · Explained math concepts in caring and encouraging environment to help Students thrive and learn
- · Created special handouts, study guides and assessments to evaluate and boost student knowledge
- Educated students on study tips and exam strategies
- Tutored students in math courses while coordinating business hours with teachers

## Projects \_

#### Android application for Café order

September 2020 - December 2020

- Development of mobile application for making online orders using Java and Android Studio.
- Fully Automated software to make easy for users
- Involved in the full life cycle of the project including analysis design, development, debugging, testing and deployment
- Wrote clean, clear, efficient, well-tested, and maintainable code
- Perform bug fixes and improve overall application's performance

#### Website for Restaurant order and reservation

January 2021 - May 2021

- Implemented responsive interface using JavaScript and HTML5 and CSS3
- Ensured layout of content is accessible on all platforms and devices
- Developed a strong knowledge of web technologies
- Self-developed the front-end and back-end of a user-friendly web application
- Tested websites and performed user testing and troubleshooting prior to live deployment
- Assessed risks associated with developing new features

### Technical Skill

 $\bullet \ \ \mathsf{Java} \cdot \mathsf{Android} \cdot \mathsf{Javascript} \cdot \mathsf{HTML5} \cdot \mathsf{CSS3} \cdot \mathsf{MySQL} \cdot \mathsf{Web} \ \mathsf{Development} \cdot \mathsf{Algorithm} \cdot \mathsf{Data} \ \mathsf{Structure} \cdot \mathsf{PHP}$ 

### Education -

#### **NAU (North American University)**

Houston, TX, USA

Overall GPA: -

3.73

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCE (EXPECTED GRADUATION: DECEMBER 2022)